<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ToastMastersClubRoleRules>
	<Role>
		<ShortName>TME</ShortName>
		<Name>ToastMaster of the Evening(TME)</Name>
		<Duty>
1) Ensure that you arrive latest by 6:45pm. Check if the main role-takers such as GE, Speakers, Timer, Grammarian, 
Ah-counter and TTM have arrived.

2) Announce and encourage all to applause and shake-hands at the change over.

3) Announce any sudden role-changes.

4) You must properly introduce all Speakers. You are to mention who is their Evaluator and the time allowed if the 
evaluator fails to do so.  You are to address all Speakers without any educational titles as Toastmasters and then 
their name.

If they have attained any titles, then you are to introduce by saying their title first then their name.

You can also introduce to the audience the background of the speaker, when this person joined Toastmasters, occupation, 
company and hobbies. 

E.g. The first speaker will be doing his P6 speech. Before his speech, I will ask his evaluator to read to ask the 
objectives of the speech. His evaluator is TM___________. Thank you. 

The speaker joined our club about six months ago; He is a sales manager with ABC Company. Speaking on the 
title: _______________. Let’s welcome TM____________ or CC, CL ____________.

5) You are to ask the Individual Evaluator to read out the objective of the Speech 

6) If the person is NOT from our own Club, then mention which club that person’s belongs to and also the position in the 
club with the level attained. (CC, ACB, ACS, ACG, ACB and ACS). You can also mention when they joined TM and which clubs 
they have founded.

7) Remember, you are to maintain the energy of the room and make adjustments to the agenda and program when it is necessary 
in order to maintain a high level meeting with consultation to the President.
		</Duty>
	</Role>
	<Role>
		<ShortName>Timer</ShortName>
		<Name>Timer</Name>
		<Duty>
		Timing.
		</Duty>
	</Role>
	<Role>
		<ShortName>Ah Counter</ShortName>
		<Name>Ah Counter</Name>
		<Duty>
		Calcute the ah, en used.
		</Duty>
	</Role>
	<Role>
		<ShortName>Grammarian</ShortName>
		<Name>Grammarian</Name>
		<Duty>
		Calcute the ah, en used.
		</Duty>
	</Role>
	<Role>
		<ShortName>TTM</ShortName>
		<Name>Table Topic Master(TTM	)</Name>
		<Duty>
		Calcute the ah, en used.
		</Duty>
	</Role>
	<Role>
		<ShortName>GE</ShortName>
		<Name>General Evaluator(GE)</Name>
		<Duty>
		Evaluate the whole meeting.
		</Duty>
	</Role>
	<Role>
		<ShortName>Joke Master</ShortName>
		<Name>Joke Master</Name>
		<Duty>
		Calcute the ah, en used.
			jjasdfasdf
			adfadf
			asdffas
		</Duty>
	</Role>
	<Role>
		<ShortName>Speaker</ShortName>
		<Name>Speaker</Name>
		<Duty>
		Calcute the ah, en used.
		</Duty>
	</Role>
	<Role>
		<ShortName>IE</ShortName>
		<Name>Individual Evaluator</Name>
		<Duty>
		Calcute the ah, en used.
		</Duty>
	</Role>
</ToastMastersClubRoleRules>